<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-04-22T12:25:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Railsconf 2014 Notes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/rails/railsconf_2014_notes/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/rails/railsconf_2014_notes/</id>
    <published>2014-04-22T12:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-22T08:41:32-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Railsconf 2014 is here! I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking notes throughout the conference. The goal is to summarize the things and post them here. I hope you are ready!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 0 - Scholars and Guides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first evening at railsconf 2014 was spent hanging out and getting acquainted with our guides. Railsconf has this awesome scholarship program where new members to the rails community can be paired with a more experienced rails programmer. The goal is to integrate, introduce, socialize and teach the mentee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to hang out with an awesome group of individuals from many different backgrounds. There were guides across the industry from &lt;a href="https://www.groupon.com/"&gt;Groupon&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://www.enova.com/"&gt;Enova&lt;/a&gt;. There were scholars from very new to just graduated &lt;a href="http://flatironschool.com/"&gt;Flat Iron School&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;How do I find a job? Am I hireable?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had great conversation about how one makes the jump from self-teaching and personal projects to being hired as a developer. I was lucky to have some people in the room that hire for their current job. There was a general theme that if you are a developer that shows a propensity to learn and stay current, then it will hard to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; find a job. Sure I summarize and it is never as simple as that, but these were encouraging words for someone just entering the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Two Camps&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though there was a general theme, there were two different camps. One camp thought that there is only so far a developer, not traditionally trained in computer science, could go. The argument was around certain challenges that are hard problems and having computer science as a background help you solve those problems faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other side really beat home the point that if you are excited about the company and committed to learning then a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; company would be excited to train/hire you. A &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; company is one that follows the philosophy that excited, knowledgeable people make the best developers. If the company places too much emphasis in mundane computer science tests, then they are not the kind of company you want to work for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a great conversation and really puts perspective on where I should focus on my learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all it was a great experience and if this is a prelude to the actual conference, then I am going to meet some amazing people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;More coming soon! Check back!&lt;/h1&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Using Middleman to Design a Static Personal Website, Part 1</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/code/using-middleman-to-design-a-static-personal-website-part-1/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/code/using-middleman-to-design-a-static-personal-website-part-1/</id>
    <published>2014-04-21T17:54:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-21T13:17:29-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ever wanted a simple, fast personal site to showcase your personal brand? Here is how I used &lt;a href="http://middlemanapp.com/"&gt;Middleman&lt;/a&gt; to create a custom, statically generated personal site and blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I decided that my website needed a bit more love. As I am getting more involved in the web development community, I needed a place that people could find and contact me. My site didn&amp;rsquo;t have to be complex. I needed something simple, fast, and a place to build from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article is split into two posts. The &lt;a href="http://noahpatterson.me/blog/code/using-middleman-to-design-a-static-personal-website-part-1/"&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; is about the project and the process. The second post (coming soon!) is how I used Middleman to do it. The second post will also include some helpful tips and tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good list of requirements with use cases is important at the start of any project. I had a few basic needs that I started out with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Content&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small blurb about me i.e. the sell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email contact&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The content is pretty straightforward, normal things that most people would want out of a personal site. Keeping it simple I decided not to implement a project page just yet. Showcasing some of my best work might be important, but I also know other web developers are keen on browsing &lt;a href="https://github.com/noahpatterson"&gt;Github repositories &lt;/a&gt; for this information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Tech&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mobile first, responsive &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world of web development conferences, meetups and happy hours people will primarily access my site on mobile. Mobile first allows these experiences to be easy and clean.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Static site&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the writing and design of the site is aided by dynamic content and templating, once the site is published it is a straightforward document based website. I wanted to use static sites for how quickly they load once published. This approach isn&amp;rsquo;t always the easiest. You need to be comfortable with html, css, command line, and markdown. Unlike &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/"&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; or some other &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Content_management_system"&gt;CMS&lt;/a&gt; the writing and publishing is done via the command line and could be unfriendly to a non-developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github pages is an awesome resource from the people at Github. If you have a simple static site you can deploy the site to Github&amp;rsquo;s servers. You&amp;rsquo;ll end up with web hosting, version control, collaboration options, and issue tracking for free! Win win.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ruby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I dive deeper and deeper into the world of Ruby I want to explore all areas that the language covers. I&amp;rsquo;ve already done Rails and Ruby programs &lt;a href="https://github.com/noahpatterson/flickrUpload"&gt;FlickrUpload&lt;/a&gt;, so I wanted to explore other ruby technologies. (I am still learning and working on this, I absolutely have more work to do).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology I wanted to use was a bit more personal and opinionated. I am firm believer that projects will solidify knowledge that tutorials or blog posts summarized. The goal of the site was not to only have an awesome site to showcase myself, but to also to teach myself more about web design, static sites, &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github pages&lt;/a&gt; and ruby that isn&amp;rsquo;t rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Use cases and user personas&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I learned anything from the the front-end development course I took at &lt;a href="http://www.thinkful.com/"&gt;Thinkful&lt;/a&gt; is that use cases and user personas are key to making sure a project is designed for the users. I needed a site that would allow people to contact me and read my blog. Here are the use cases I created:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fellow web developer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a fellow web developer and someone that understands technology &lt;em&gt;Fellow web developer&lt;/em&gt; is primarily interested in connecting with me via social media. &lt;em&gt;Fellow web developer&lt;/em&gt; also wants to see some of the projects that I have worked on. &lt;em&gt;Fellow web developer&lt;/em&gt; understands Github is a great place to do that. &lt;em&gt;Fellow web developer&lt;/em&gt; would understand any quirky easter eggs in my design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Googler&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Googler&lt;/em&gt; has a problem. They have been trying for hours to solve a bug in their application. They&amp;rsquo;ve found nothing be unanswered Stack Overflow questions. And they don&amp;rsquo;t need &lt;a href="http://www.hulu.com/watch/536145"&gt;more cowbell&lt;/a&gt;. Luckily for &lt;em&gt;The Googler&lt;/em&gt; they found a post on my blog about their specific problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Tweeter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://birds.audubon.org/birdid/search#block-facetapi-FT0LhKpqhCSyyrwU4uxdyeyJe96iSqUf"&gt;Chirp, whistle, hi&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;The Tweeter&lt;/em&gt; knows all of the calls of the social web. &lt;em&gt;The Tweeter&lt;/em&gt; constantly refreshes Twitter for the best blog posts their peers are recommending. &lt;em&gt;The Tweeter&lt;/em&gt; will find links to my blog as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Employer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Who is this guy and how can he help me?&amp;rdquo; is &lt;em&gt;The Employer&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; primary question. They want to see my work and learn more about me. &lt;em&gt;The Employer&lt;/em&gt; wouldn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily understand the quirky easter eggs in my design and would be confused why the code was showing. They would primarily be interested in the blog and Github link.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Is that all?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a good base to start I knew I could always add more scope and user personas as the project was further along. I want the project to grow as it needs to. If new requirements show up later, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be difficult to work out  a new scope and any new user personas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Fin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this has given you an idea of how I started this project and some of the processes that went into brainstorming it. In the next part we&amp;rsquo;ll go over the actual implementation and I&amp;rsquo;ll give you some tips and tricks that I discovered along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Part 2 Coming Soon!&lt;/h2&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Immersive Meetups</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/learning/immersive-meetups/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/learning/immersive-meetups/</id>
    <published>2013-04-25T22:46:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-19T13:57:14-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tonight I attended a Meetup about web design process and strategy. Am I a designer? Only fledgling. Am I a part of the community? No but I am trying to be. Why then would I even try to attend a meet up about design? Why would I subject myself to the awkwardness of explaining that &amp;ldquo;No am I not a designer. I&amp;rsquo;m not even a web developer yet.&amp;quot; It&amp;rsquo;s a scary prospect attending a community meet up in a community you have no real connection to.  Before I go into the reason and explanation of why I am doing these things, lets dive into a bit of a thought experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Your crazy idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets say that you have this crazy idea. The idea is very different from every idea that you have had in the past. Odds are the idea is vague, the implementation is challenging and you don&amp;rsquo;t have the skills to start. However you are convinced this the idea is worth pursuing. If only you could gather the skills, the knowledge and the motivation to do it yourself. How would you go about pursuing this idea?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In language studies I read that to truly know and understand a new language you have to be immersed in that language. Your day to day routines have to be in that language. Your ideas and frustrations have to be expressed in that language. Only then will you be able to communicate with people speaking that language. Most of the time language students travel to the region where they can live the language, where everyone around them speaks the language. Why don&amp;rsquo;t we learn all new skills the same way? If you are a plumber you need to be immersed in plumbing (sigh unintentional pun). If you are a locksmith you better understand all the different kinds of locks. If you are a web designer or developer you need to know how people design for the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;My crazy idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to learn web design and web development. I am immersing myself in the world and I am trying to fully understand what it means to be a web designer/developer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Immersion Creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we create this immersive atmosphere when we cannot just travel to a foreign land? My current idea is to fill as much of my life with web dev and design as possible. I want to speak web dev, sleep web dev, and who knows &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/TechBreakfast/"&gt;eat&lt;/a&gt; web dev. When I am not working my day job I am working on Thinkful coursework. When I am walking to work I am listening to web dev/design podcasts like &lt;a href="http://shoptalkshow.com/"&gt;Shoptalk Show&lt;/a&gt;. I bookmark articles about web dev/design to read later. I follow and keep up with designers in the community via twitter. I attend Meetup groups and conferences about web dev/design. I am fully integrating this work into my life and I believe if you want to tackle that project or idea you have, you need to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Web Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily in the web design and web development community there are talented people that are willing to teach other potentially talented people their craft. The Web community is taking all of the benefits of the old trade/apprenticeship model and tweaking it for today&amp;rsquo;s internet filled world. Through the use of Meetup groups and Twitter we can connect with smart people in the community and we can pick their brains to gather critical knowledge about our work. In the web community it is almost required that the most experienced members teach their craft. In DC groups like &lt;a href="http://refresh-dc.org/"&gt;RefreshDC&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/washdctech/#"&gt;DC Tech&lt;/a&gt; encourage participation by all and create fun learning events for the DC web community. DC design and development agencies like &lt;a href="http://istrategylabs.com/"&gt;iStrategyLabs&lt;/a&gt; are also fully involved in teaching others their skills. I believe the companies see it as a way to build and eventually procure the most talented members of the community. Win, win. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Realism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end we&amp;rsquo;ll see if my efforts will help me meet my goal of joining the web dev/design community. We have to be realistic when thinking of the outcome of our efforts. I have set my goal as a challenge but I also have to be happy if I only attain parts of the goal. If at the very least I come out of this journey with a basic understanding of the web dev/develop world, I will still be able to apply my new knowledge to other projects and goals. Again, win, win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Thinkful update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working hard on finishing up a first draft on my personal site.  It is clear now that designing is a process where iteration is key. The first project I really designed, &lt;a href="http://blog.albino-squirrel.com/blog/2013/04/20/wmata-nextbus-redesign/"&gt;WMATA Redesign&lt;/a&gt;, was a struggle. While I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have the best design I do think it is a step in the right direction. For my personal site I am taking all the knowledge I have gained of the &amp;lsquo;design process&amp;rsquo; and I have started to formulate new strategies. I really feel that practice makes perfect in website design. The more projects that I do the better off I will be in learning how to design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WMATA Nextbus Redesign</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/css/wmata-nextbus-redesign/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/css/wmata-nextbus-redesign/</id>
    <published>2013-04-20T19:03:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-19T14:40:08-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the &lt;a href="http://www.thinkful.com"&gt;Thinkful&lt;/a&gt; class I am taking we were tasked to use our newly learned information about design to redesign a website. I choose one I thought didn&amp;rsquo;t quite reach it&amp;rsquo;s potential. A website that I use. A website that my friends rely on. A website that the people in Washington, DC use everyday. &lt;a href="http://www.wmata.com/rider_tools/nextbus/arrivals.cfm"&gt;WMATA Nextbus Finder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me guide you through what is wrong with the website, my process to tackle the problem, and finally some prototypes of how it could look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WMATA Nextbus Finder is used by people in Washington, DC to find when a public transit bus is arriving at their chosen stop. The site allows you to do a number of additional things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/screenshotcomment.png" alt='wmata nextbus screenshot with comments'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Find additional information about transportation in Washington, DC&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;See live maps of the locations of buses by route&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Look up route time tables&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Select the specific route the user is looking for to see the arrival times&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;See the estimated arrival times of the buses in the route the user selected&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;See alternative routes that come to the stop the user selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just having these options for public transit is extremely convenient, I use the Finder all the time. However I find the Finder extremely hard to use. There seems to be a simpler way to navigate and gain the information. Why isn&amp;rsquo;t the site designed better? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps WMATA doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the bandwidth to design for this page. Perhaps they don&amp;rsquo;t care. Perhaps the designers just don&amp;rsquo;t understand how people use the site. All of these are examples of how a solid design process of need finding, user testing, and proper work flow could help design a better site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever the reason I believe my design prototypes can shed some light on how the site and use of the information could be improved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What is wrong with this site?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The design of the main website is not the same as the design of the Nextbus Finder&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Useful map information is loaded on another page&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Selection of route information is slow and awkward&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Selecting another route clears the current route&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;There is no information on whether the alternative routes are useful to get the user to their destination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;My Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I analyzed the current site and asked friends for feedback on what was missing. Ease of use and not knowing which bus to take were the biggest complaints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I sketched of some ideas of what the site could look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/wmatawire1.png" alt='wmata nextbus sketch'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took some of the better ideas and made wire frames to get a more structured and neat view of the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/myImage.png" alt='wmata nextbus redesign wire frame'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally I prototyped two of the best ideas in HTML and CSS. The sites are by no means finished but I think they give potential users a good idea of how they would gain public transit information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Explanation of the prototypes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Redesign1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This different take on the WMATA Nextbus Finder focuses on a large map and clean UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/wmataredesigncomments2.png" alt='wmata nextbus redesign 1 bus arrival zones'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Upon login a favorites button will keep track of stops that the user use often&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The live map will track the route the user has selected and the buses that are on the route (this uses WMATA&amp;rsquo;s current style of live map, some improvements could be found here too)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The map can expand to the whole page&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The user can search for directions, not just a specific route and have WMATA&amp;rsquo;s current trip planner find the available routes to take&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The user can still search for specific routes&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Arrivals are in a clean UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Redesign2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This radical prototype focuses on a new view that facilitates quick glance updates of bus arrival times&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/wmataredesigncomments1.png" alt='wmata nextbus redesign 2 bus arrival zones'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A clean, modern Navigation&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A favorites button will keep track of stops that you use often once you login&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A prominent visual display of arriving buses&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Buses on the route, showing what street, and how long until its arrival. These buses travel down the screen from green to red as the bus gets closer&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Route and/or stop selector using easy searching&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Alternative route information that will populate the upcoming buses area with the selected route&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Bus arrival zones use common knowledge of green=OK, yellow=caution and red=Bad. The sections will represent the time the user has until a bus gets to their selected stop. Green buses are further away and they have time. Yellow bus are close and they should leave. Red buses are at their stop and they will likely miss the bus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the Thinkful project was really inspiring. The project allowed me to gather my ideas for a better public transit system into a living and breathing idea.  I learned a lot about design and designing actual concrete ideas for the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>WMATA DC Next Bus App Sketches</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/css/wmata-dc-next-bus-app-sketches/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/css/wmata-dc-next-bus-app-sketches/</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T16:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-19T13:57:01-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some Initial sketches of a WMATA DC next bus web redesign. This is part of a thinkful project. More to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/images/wmataapp.jpg" alt='wmata next bus sketches'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Thinkful Update</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/learning/thinkful-update/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/learning/thinkful-update/</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T01:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-19T14:36:17-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;These next few weeks are about design. This is an area that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of experience in but I hope will teach me a lot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can say that reading about design and to a larger extent taking a course about web design/development has opened my mind to examples in everyday life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One example that continues to irk me is the lack of decently designed mobile restaurant pages in Washington DC. Almost every restaurant website that I have been to recently has redirected me to a mobile site, given me unclear instructions on how to view the full site, not provided a responsive layout, and is generally crap. The sites are ugly, not functional, and usually only three buttons: menu, directions, contact us. OK so you included menu, that&amp;rsquo;s probably why I am there anyway &lt;click&gt; oh it&amp;rsquo;s just a .pdf that takes forever to download and is out of date? Great. Sigh seriously they are all crap. I wonder if any other cities have this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s back to trying to find dinner on my phone &lt;headdesk&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
